Finding Aid for the Sekerak Family Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Sekerak Family Collection
1943-1956
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0585
.42 linear_feet
Scope and Contents
This .21 linear feet collection contains 60 individual travel postcards and four souvenir booklets, in 27 file folders. Some of the postcards were mailed and others are blank. The majority of the mailed cards were addressed to Mary, Anna, or George Sekerak in Cleveland, Ohio. The cards are arranged alphabetically by state, then by location within the state. The years that are indicated in the finding aid are from the postmarked date on the mailed cards.
These postcards were donated by Sally Gross.
- Alabama
  - Birmingham – R. H. Wharton Bridge – 1952 – color
- Florida
  - Bradenton – Summers Motor Court – 1952 – color
  - Clearwater – Air View of Clearwater Beach – 1956 – color (oversized)
  - Clearwater – Gray Moss Inn – 1948 – color
  - General – Greetings from Florida – color (oversized)
  - Hollywood – The Great Masterpiece – 1954 - color
  - Hollywood – Moonlite Over Hollywood Blvd. – 1953 – color
  - Largo – A Tropical Paradise – 1954 – color
  - Miami – A Flamingo Nesting at Hialeah Race Course – 1953 – color
  - Miami – Gesu Catholic Church – 1956 – color
  - Miami – Souvenir Booklet – 1952 – color
    - City Yacht Basin
    - Parrot Jungle
    - Biscayne Blvd.
    - Racing Down the Backstretch, Hialeah Park
    - Downtown Miami from Miami River
    - Library in Bayfront Park
    - The Mercy Hospital
    - Miami – The Magic Metropolis
    - Greetings from Miami
    - S. S. Florida – Havana Bound
    - Bayfront Park and Biscayne Blvd. Hotels
    - Flamingos and Nests at Hialeah Race Course, Hialeah
    - Beautiful Bayfront Park
    - Moon over Miami
    - Flagler Street
    - Merrick Building – University of Miami
    - Miami’s Famed Bayfront Park
    - Biscayne Blvd.
  - Miami Beach – After Visiting the Fountain of Youth – 1950 – color
  - Miami Beach – Fur Trading in the Everglades – 1953 – color
  - Miami Beach – Indian Creek at 63rd Street – 1952 – color
  - Miami Beach – Lincoln Road at Night – 1955 – color
  - Miami Beach – Luxurious Hotels Along Collins Avenue – 1952 – color
  - Miami Beach – Orange Groves, Sunny Skies, Sparkling Lakes – 1951 – color
  - Miami Beach – A Peaceful Tropical Lagoon – 1952 – color
  - Miami Beach – Scene Along Indian Creek – 1952 – color
    - Miami Beach – Souvenir Booklet – 1952 – color
    - Sunrise on the Florida Coast
    - Luxurious Hotels
    - Magnificent Ocean Front Hotels
    - Sun Bathers under the Palms
    - Ocean Front Hotels
    - Playground of the America’s at Night
    - Moon on Miami Beach
    - Luxurious Hotel Row, Collins Avenue
    - Greetings from Miami Beach
    - Swaying Palms at a Typical Miami Beach
    - A Bayfront Home in Miami Beach
    - Hotels and Indian Creek Looking South from 41st Street
    - Collins Ave., Showing Martinique, Delmonico, Coronet, Casablanca and
      - The Lombardy Hotels
    - The Shelbourne, Nautilus and Shore Club Hotels
    - Famous Lincoln Road and Collins Avenue
    - Causeways Linking Miami and Miami Beach
    - Forty-First Street Bridge and Ocean Front Hotels
    - Greetings from Miami Beach
  - Osteen – Lemon Bluff, near Sanford, Florida – 1953 – color
  - Saint Petersburg – A Hedge of Flame Vine and Hibiscus – 1949 – color
  - Saint Petersburg – Hotel Soreno – 1949 – color
  - Saint Petersburg – Sun-tanning – 1954 – color
  - Sarasota – Stately Living Amidst Stately Royal Palms – 1955 – color
  - West Palm Beach – A Thrilling Catch Off Florida – 1951 – color
- Georgia
  - Atlanta – Cyclorama. Grant Park – 1956 – color
  - Fort Benning – Souvenir Booklet – 1944 – color
    - Entrance to East For Benning
    - Officers’ Club
    - Paratroopers in Mass Jump
    - The Chapel
    - Infantry Tanks Ready for Action
    - Commandant’s Quarters
    - Russ Pool
    - Night Firing
    - Infantry School Building
    - Old Glory
    - Tank Attack
    - Partial View of Lawson Field
    - Officers’ Club Swimming Pool
    - Rainbow Avenue
    - Tank Crossing Stream under Artillery Fire
    - Barracks
    - Wold Avenue
    - Parachute Troops
- Louisiana
  - Along The Bayou – color
  - Monroe – Bridge over Ouachita River – 1945 – color
  - New Orleans – Brulatour Courtyard – color
  - New Orleans – The Cabildo – color
  - New Orleans – The Corn Fence – color
  - New Orleans – Court of Two Sisters – color (5 views)
  - New Orleans – Courtyard and Prison Rooms in the Cabildo – color
  - New Orleans – Courtyard of Little Theatre – color
  - New Orleans – Felix’s Bar and Restaurant – color (2 copies)
  - New Orleans – French Market – color
  - New Orleans – Hibiscus – 1952 – color
  - New Orleans – Iron Grille – color
  - New Orleans – Jackson Square – color
  - New Orleans – Kinsey Courtyard – 1952 – color
  - New Orleans – Old St Louis Cemetery – color
  - New Orleans – The Pakenham’s Oaks – color
  - New Orleans – Pirates Alley – color
  - New Orleans – The Roosevelt – color
  - New Orleans – Unloading Bananas – color
  - New Orleans – Souvenir Booklet – 1952 – color
    - Entrance in Garden District
    - Audubon Park and View of Zoo
    - Canal Street at Night
    - Vaults of Old St Louis Cemetery
    - The Old Absinthe House
    - St. Louis Cathedral – Jackson Square
    - Skyline of New Orleans from the Harbor
    - Aerial View of the Sugar Bowl
    - Huey P. Long Bridge
    - International Trade Mart
    - Fan Window in Governor Claiborne’s Home
    - Aerial View of New Orleans
    - Pontalba Apartment Building – Jackson Square
    - Courtyard and Prison in Cabildo
    - Charity Hospital
    - Pirate’s Alley
    - Lacework in Iron
    - Canal Street During Mardi Gras
- Mississippi
  - Grenada – Cotton Leaving the Gin – 1943 – color
  - Pascagoula – The Longfellow House – 1953 – color
  - Pascagoula – Old Spanish Fort and Museum – 1953 – natural color
- Tennessee
  - Great Smoky Mountain National Park – The New Gatlinburg Inn – 1948 – color
  - Great Smoky Mountain National Park – Rainbow Falls on Mt. LeConte – 1948 – color
  - Knoxville – Norris Dam – 1955 – color
  - Nashville – Monterey Motel – color
  - Nashville – Post Office – 1951 – color
  - Nashville – Veteran’s Administration Hospital – 1951 – color
- Virginia
  - Quantico – Military Headquarters – black and white
  - Quantico – R. R. Station – black and white
  - [Quantico] – Commandant Inspecting Marines – black and white